（忆往昔）
出来 鬼魂 鬼魂 鬼魂
Here, ghosty, ghosty, ghosty!
出来 不管你在哪儿
Come out, come out wherever you are.
我不相信鬼魂
I don't believe in ghosts.
摄像机拍到了鬼 灵魂摄影
The camera caught ghost in the film? Spirit photography.
你以为怨魂是怎么产生的
How do you think angry spirits are born?
无法释怀 无法前行
Can't let it go. They can't move on.
停留在这里多年
They stood here for years.
他们都觉得空洞 害怕
They all feel disembodied, scared.
还说鬼魂呢
Talking about ghosts.
不
No!
黑暗 她救了我
The darkness … she saved me.
我们是联系在一起的 迪恩
We're bound, Dean.
她感谢了我
She thanked me.
- 谢你什么 - 释放了她
- For what? - Setting her free.
阿玛拉应该就是黑暗
I think Amara is the Darkness.
那女孩身体里有魔鬼
The devil's in that girl!
阿玛拉饿了 她正在长身体
Amara's hungry. She's a growing girl.
外面有个古老的邪恶
So we have some ancient evil out there,
每天都愈发强大
just getting stronger by the day.
我想要那个孩子
I want that child.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
那孩子吃灵魂
The child eats souls.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
阿玛拉
Amara?
我说了
I said…
我饿了
I'm hungry.
（如今）
（马萨诸塞州 福尔河）
亲身来到这个房间感觉更恐怖了
This place is way creepier in person.
当然了
Hell, yeah, it is.
抓鬼特工队可捕捉不到那股愤怒的感觉
Ghost facers can't capture the…rage vibes.
你觉得我们会看到什么吗
You think we'll see anything?
知道我为什么要这间房吗
You know why I got this room?
据说有很多超自然现象
It's supposed to get the heavy paranormal action.
现在我们变成《闪灵》了
And now we're in "The Shining."
我去
Oh, crap.
- 她要来抓你了 - 别闹了
- She's coming to get you. - Shut up!
别担心 有我在呢
Don't worry. I'm here.
我们不就为这个来的吗
This is what we came here for, right?
门就是松了
The hinges are falling.
怎么了
What?
（莉兹房间）
（莉兹·波顿床铺早餐式旅馆博物馆 勿扰）
[邪恶力量 第11季第5集]
找到黑暗的位置了吗
Don't suppose you got a 20 on the Darkness.
我之前还以为是查到了什么
Uh, well, I thought I had something earlier.
半个小镇突然发疯 到处袭人
Half a town flipped their gourds and started attacking people,
结果是因为吃了患了狂犬病的负鼠肉
but it turns out they'd eaten rabid possum meat.
他们知道负鼠就是大老鼠吧
Okay, they do realize that possum is a giant rat, right?
其实是有袋类动物
It's a marsupial.
不是重点 看这个
Not the point. Look, check this out.
一对情侣在马萨诸塞州福尔河被人用斧子砍死
Um, "A couple was ax-murdered in Fall River, Massachusetts,
案发地为 听好了
at"… wait for it…
莉兹·波顿床铺早餐式旅馆博物馆
"The Lizzie Borden Bed and Breakfast Museum."
- 床铺早餐式旅馆加博物馆吗 - 嗯
- A b&b and a museum. - Yeah.
完全不像黑店嘛
That doesn't sound like a tourist trap at all.
是这样
I mean, the thing is,
那家旅馆是莉兹·波顿本人的房子
the inn was Lizzie Borden's actual house.
1892年 她在那家里砍死了爸爸和她继母
In 1892, she hacked up her dad and stepmom there.
至少是据传如此
Or… or allegedly hacked them up.
她被判了无罪
She was acquitted,
余生一直生活在福尔河
ended up spending the rest of her days in Fall River.
但却遭镇民的迫害
hounded and persecuted by the townspeople.
你觉得是报复杀人吗
So you're thinking revenge killing?
为什么现在啊
Why now?
可能是哪个看多了杀人狂电影的
It was probably just some psycho fan.
变态粉丝
who's seen too many slasher flicks.
有可能吧 但旅馆门锁得好好的
Could be, But the inn was locked up,
没有人进出的痕迹
no signs of entry or exit,
六位住客
a half a dozen guests,
无一人看到或听到人闯入
none of whom saw or heard any intruders.
或许凶手很厉害呢
Well, maybe the murderer was actually competent.
等等 我知道怎么回事了
Wait a minute. I know what this is.
这跟你对连环杀手的
This has something to do with your freaky fetish for…
奇怪迷恋有关
for serial killers.
算不上迷恋
It's not a fetish.
你本来就想去看那栋房子
You've always wanted to see that house.
迪恩 死了两个人啊
Dean, two people are dead.
还死在莉兹·波顿家里
in Lizzie Borden's home.
我们没有阿玛拉的线索 不如去看看嘛
We got no leads on Amara. I say we check this out.
而且 整个波顿家族都埋在福尔河
Besides, the entire Borden clan are buried in Fall River,
包括莉兹本人
including Lizzie.
你想拿小卡怎么办
What do you want to do about Cass?
他连看《火线》正看得欢呢
Oh, he's knee-deep in binge-watching "The wire."
刚开始看第二季
Just started season 2.
嗯 他一时半会儿是停不下来了
Oh, yeah, he's not coming out any time soon.
好吧
All right.
波顿旅馆 有什么可以帮您的吗
Borden b&b. How may I help you?
莉兹还有自己的娃娃了
So I guess now Lizzie Borden has her own doll.
疯眼睛有点过头了
Yeah, went a little overboard on the crazy eyes.
不 现在已经不是犯罪现场了
No, it's absolutely not a crime scene anymore.
房间已经清理干净了
Look, the room's been cleaned,
而且你都不在那层楼
and you're not even on the same floor.
没必要取消…
Th-there's no reason to canc…
大家还对凶杀的事心有余悸 是吧
People still freaked out about the murders, huh?
有些人则觉得刺激
Some find it exciting.
二位有什么需要吗
Can I help you boys?
嗯 我们读到了惨剧的报道
Yeah. We'd read about the tragedy,
我是个历史迷
and I'm a bit of a history buff.
我想问问
And I just wanted to ask,
你觉得凶案跟
do you think the killings.
莉兹·波顿有任何关系吗
had anything to do with Lizzie Borden…
我是指她的鬼魂什么的
I mean, her ghost, or whatever?
大概就是个疯狂粉丝闯了进来 是吧
Probably just some crazed fan broke in, right?
这些问题很好
These are great questions, guys…
如果是住客问 我们一般就回答了
Ones we usually answer for our paying guests.
好吧
Right.
梅森
Mason!
你忘记取消面包店的订单了
You forgot to cancel the bakery order!
妈妈 我招待客人呢
Mom, I'm with customers.
两百块的丹麦面包 结果没人吃
$200 worth of Danish and no guests to eat it!
他们能吃点啊
These guys can put away a few.
要从你的工资里扣
It's coming out of your paycheck.
当然了
Of course it is.
跟家人共事有时是挺难办
Working with family can be tough.
20年了
20 years.
二位选房间吧
And you have your pick of rooms.
我们就住那对情侣住的房间
We'll take the one the couple was in.
死去的那对情侣吗
The deceased couple?
我们大老远来见鬼的
We came a long way to see some ghosts.
那儿应该是最不安生的地方
We figured there's the most unrest there.
我们现在不租那个房间
Uh, we're not renting that room right now…
出于敬意
out of respect.
但早晚得恢复生意嘛
But you got to get back on that horse sometime.
真走运 我们刚重装了房间
Lucky. We redid the room.
太好了
Great.
既然我们是住客了
And now that we are paying guests,
你那晚有看到或听到什么不寻常的事吗
did you hear or see anything unusual that night?
他们尖叫之前没有
Not till we heard the screams.
我叫妈妈留在楼下 自己跑了上去
I told mom to stay downstairs, and I ran up there.
天呐 那个血啊
Oh, God. Blood.
那对情侣是什么人
And who was the couple?
就是本地的孩子
Local kids.
那姑娘没什么特别的 但那男的
I mean, nothing special about the girl, but the guy…
他是原波顿家族的后裔
he was a descendant of the original Bordens.
多谢
Thanks.
我都不知道眼睛该往哪放
I don't know where to put my eyes.
我想吐
I think I'm gonna throw up.
我们被花饰包围了
We're surrounded by doilies.
到处都是
They're everywhere.
那旅馆老板
Okay, you think the innkeeper.
坑我们之前也不说一声
might have mentioned this before he ripped us off.
看来你得另找间房了
I guess you're gonna have to get yourself another room.
这原来是莉兹的房间
Because this was Lizzie's original room,
- 我是不会让出去的 - 你四岁啊
- and I'm not giving it up. - What are you, 4?
看啊
Look at that.
跟网上对楼上房间的
That jibes with what people online.
传说相吻合
have been saying about the upstairs…
空屋传来哭声 脚步声 灯光闪烁
Crying in empty rooms, footsteps, buzzing lights.
衣橱里没有暗格或密道
No secret panels or passageways in the closet.
世界上最小的厕所没什么问题
Well, the world's smallest bathroom is clean.
那是什么味儿
what is that smell?
好像是这个
I think it's this.
好像是薰衣草花露水
It's like a lavender toilet water.
瓶装花露水
Bottled toilet water?
你喷个什么劲
Why do you keep spraying it?
我就想看看按的那个东东好不好使
I just wanted to see if the squeezy thing worked.
好像是当香水用的
I think it was supposed to be a perfume or something.
好吧 我去旅馆其他地方看看
All right, I'm gonna go check out the rest of the inn.
这下我一身奶奶味儿了
'cause now I got grandma all over me, so…
（闲人免进）
（我在莉兹·波顿床铺早餐式旅馆博物馆幸存了一晚）
（莉兹·波顿床铺早餐式旅馆博物馆）
莉兹不在阁楼里
Yeah, no Lizzie in the attic.
但我找到一台自制电磁干扰机
But I did find a homemade EMF generator.
把那东西关了
Turned that beast off,
结果呢 没有信号了
and what do you know… no more signal.
令人震惊啊
Shocking.
闪烁的电灯
The, uh, flickering lights…
跟埋在墙里的计时器连着呢
Wired to timers buried in the walls.
拜托
Come on.
还有 看看这个
Oh, and check out this baby.
盖着音响系统呢
Covering up our very own sound system.
我把这个从墙里搜了出来
I, uh, fished this out of the wall.
空屋的哭声
Crying in empty rooms.
还有呢 跑步的脚步声
And there's more… running footsteps,
听不清的恐怖低语
uh, creepy whispers you can't quite make out,
还有一声马桶冲水 那个没搞明白
one flushing toilet… not quite sure what that's about.
这地方就是假的
The whole place is a hoax, man.
就像我说的 是家黑店
It's a tourist trap, just like I said.
但我们还是不知道那对情侣怎么被人砍死的
Yeah, but we still don't know how that couple got axed.
凶手如何进出的啊
I mean, how did the killer get in and out?
不知道 不如我们边喝啤酒吃龙虾卷
I don't know. Why don't we sherlock that over a beer.
边破案 怎么样
and a lobster roll, okay?
我得赶紧离开这间花饰棺材
I got to get out of this doily coffin.
多谢
Thanks.
马德森警探 我是柯林斯探员
Detective Madsen? Agent Collins.
你们之前还不是联调局的呢
You weren't feds earlier.
我和我搭档是卧底来调查
Well, um, my partner and I were undercover.
之前的案件的
investigating the original murders.
那我妈妈被杀时你在哪呢
Where the hell were you when my mom was being…
我很遗憾 坎普先生
I'm so very sorry, Mr. Kemper.
我们会找到行凶的混蛋的
We're gonna find the son of a bitch who's doing this.
他刚刚锁好门
He had just finished locking up.
旅馆里只有他和坎普太太
No one was inside but him and Mrs. Kemper.
员工几小时前就回家了
Staff went home hours ago.
第一起凶案也没有嫌疑人吗
And no suspects for the first murders, either?
我是盖布利尔探员
I'm agent Gabriel.
我之前看到附近有个人
Listen, I saw a guy hanging around earlier,
在拍照
snapping some photos,
我想跟他说话时 他跑掉了
and he ran away when I tried to make contact.
我猜猜 矮 胖 娃娃脸
Let me guess… short, chunky, baby-faced?
没错
Yeah, that's him.
那是伦 人畜无害的
That's Len. Total teddy bear.
我们是高中同学
I went to high school with him.
他超喜欢鬼魂之类的事 但他没坏心
Obsessed with ghosts, but harmless.
鬼魂啊
Ghosts?
这真是个问题吗
Is that a real issue around here?
据商会说 绝对是呢
According to the chamber of commerce, absolutely.
好吧
Right.
我会派个警官去伦那里录下口供
I'll send an officer over to Len, get a statement from him.
这样吧 你们挺忙了
You know what? You guys got your hands full.
我们去吧
We'll, uh… we'll drop by.
- 多谢 - 不客气
- Thanks. - You betcha.
目前没有任何闹鬼的迹象
Well, so far we got squat that says ghost.
跟我们毫不沾边
or anything remotely us.
或许不是我们一般的案子
So maybe it's not our usual kind of gig.
或许这是个连环杀手
Maybe we're dealing with a serial killer.
那你就开心了 是吧
Yeah, you'd love that, wouldn't you?
柯林斯探员
Agent Collins.
我是马德森警探 又发生了一起案件
This is Detective Madsen. There's been another victim.
- 是吗 - 发生在邻郡
- Really? - Accident next county.
- 天呐 - 我已经过去了
- God. - I'm there now.
嗯 多谢告知
No. Thanks for letting me know.
不客气
You're welcome.
又一人死在斧子下
Another ax vic.
这起案件离旅馆好几英里呢
This one miles from the b&b.
莉兹离家了
Lizzie left home.
看来是啊
Apparently.
好吧 我去犯罪现场
All right, I'll take the crime scene.
你去找伦
You take Len.
谁发现的尸体
Who found the body?
保姆在家带孩子
Babysitter was home with the kid,
在车道上发现了爸爸
found dad in the driveway.
天呐
Geez.
谢谢
Thanks.
我听到乔迪的爸爸在外面停了车
I heard Jordie's dad pull up outside,
然后有人大喊了一声
and then there was this shout.
我去看
I went to look,
还没看见人 就先看见血了
and I saw the blood before I saw him.
我还以为是有人洒了油漆
I thought someone had spilled paint.
那之前呢
And what about before?
你注意到什么异常情况了吗
I mean, did you notice anything out of the ordinary?
声音 气味 任何细节都行
A sound, smell? There's no detail too small.
没有 跟往常一样
No, it was like any other night.
妈妈
Mom!
乔迪 你没事吧
Jordie. Are you all right?
他看到什么了吗
Did he see anything?
没有 他一直在家里的
No, he was inside the whole time.
夫人 我是联调局的柯林斯探员
Ma'am, um, Agent Collins with the FBI.
我知道这不是个好时机
I understand this is a terrible time,
但如果可以 我想问你几个…
but if you can manage, I would love to ask you a few…
你得赶紧离开我家
You need to get out of my house is what you need to do.
当然 我可以明天再来
Of course. Uh, we can do this tomorrow.
出去
Get out!
没想到能在这儿看见她
Didn't expect to see her here.
得会享乐嘛
Well, got to live your bliss.
你是个莉兹·波顿的
Well, you are a Lizzie Borden…
看来粉丝都不足以形容你
I don't think "fan" covers it.
铁杆粉
A…Superfan.
也是博物馆管理员
A-and curator.
你今晚去旅馆就为了这个吗
And is that what you were doing tonight at the b&b?
做管理
Curating?
我
I-I, uh…
伦 你还是说实话好
Len, it's best just to go with the truth here.
我是想拍张莉兹鬼魂的照片
I-I was trying to get a picture of Lizzie's ghost.
你当时拿的是那个吗
And is that what I saw you with?
嗯 是维多利亚时代的
Yeah, it's, uh… it's what the Victorians used,
专门拍鬼魂的
for spirit photography.
你用这玩意拍到什么鬼了吗
And have you captured any caspers on that thing?
我在莉兹家见到过她
Well, I've seen Lizzie at her house.
她是一团纤弱灰色的阴影
She's this wispy, gray shadow,
但拍却拍不到
but she never shows up on film.
或许我该改用高清相机
Maybe I should go high-def.
为什么不进去
Why not go inside?
我现在不再被允许进旅馆了
I'm not exactly allowed at the inn anymore.
有那么一小张限制令
There… there's a minor restraining order.
还有一张禁口令
And there's a gag order not to…
不许我谈起那张限制令
talk about the restraining order.
但你是联邦探员嘛
But you're a federal agent.
别遮遮掩掩 伦
Buried the lead there a little, Len.
跟我说说那张限制令的事吧
Why don't you tell me about the restraining order?
那是莉兹的155岁生日
It was Lizzie's 155th birthday.
我订不到莉兹的房间
I couldn't get Lizzie's room,
就住进了地下室
so I stayed in the basement…
住了几天
…for a couple days.
几周 我又没打扰到谁
Weeks. I wasn't bothering anybody.
这么说 你对旅馆挺了解喽
So it's safe to say that you know the inn pretty well.
我问问你
Let me ask you…
你今晚有没有觉得有什么古怪
Did anything about tonight strike you as weird?
就是你敲窗
Just you banging on the window.
- 你的聊天室开启了 - 天呐 糟糕
- Your chat room is open. - Oh, god, no.
我原定主持一场
I'm supposed to lead a live chat.
关于福尔河斧子杀人案的直播聊天
about the ax murders in Fall River.
我不是莉兹新闻频道啊
I'm not Lizzie CNN!
真不知道怎么会有人那么想呢
Yeah, I don't know why anyone would think that.
我这就关掉 等下
I'll close it down. Be right back.
好吧
Okay.
两天四起斧子杀人案 毫无线索
Four ax murders in two days, no leads.
整个小镇都慌了 像大清洗一样
The whole town's panicking like it's the Purge.
也不是整个小镇
Yeah, not the whole town.
平斯基太太对丈夫
Mrs. Pinski doesn't seem too broken up.
惨死在车道上似乎并不很伤心呢
over the fact that her husband was butchered in the driveway.
你看到尸体了 她那是太震惊
You saw the body. She's in shock.
那也还是…
Still.
人们对丧亲的反应很奇怪的
People have freaky-ass reactions to loss.
你在哪看到这个的
Where did you see this?
一个关于鬼魂的网站吗
A site about ghosts?
超自然网
Th-the paranormal.
伦 你真心是我见过的最不会撒谎的人了
Len, you might be the worst liar I've ever met.
告诉我你是在哪见过这个标志的
Tell me where you've seen this symbol.
我可以带你去警局 在那儿问你
I can take you down to the station and ask you there,
但那就得惊动当地警方了
but then we've got to involve the local police,
记得你的限制令吗
your restraining order.
好吧
Okay.
Okay, uh…
几晚前 我在莉兹家外
I was outside Lizzie's house a couple nights ago.
就是想拍张她的照片
t-trying to catch a picture of her.
我刚刚还以为你是…没事了
For a second, I thought you were… never mind.
你是迷路了 还是住这家旅馆
Are you lost or staying at the inn?
是就好了
I wish I were.
我想看莉兹砍死父母的地方
I want to see where Lizzie axed her folks.
就是这里
Well, uh, you were looking at it.
至少是一半的地方
Half of it.
安德鲁·波顿的尸体就是在那儿发现的
That's where they found Andrew Borden.
瘫倒在客厅的沙发上
Slumped over the couch in the sitting…room.
抱歉 你多大了
I'm sorry. Uh, how old are you?
可怜的莉兹啊 我最近在读她的故事
Poor Lizzie. I've been reading up on her.
她父母好糟糕
Her parents sucked.
是啊
I totally agree!
莉兹完全被历史误解了
Lizzie has been so misunderstood by history.
她叔叔显然有
It's pretty obvious her uncle.
- 更强的动机和机会 - 不
- had the stronger motive and opportunity. - Oh, no.
的确是莉兹砍死了他们
Lizzie definitely hacked them.
看她的眼睛就知道 那是连环杀人犯的眼睛
You can see it in her eyes… serial-killer eyes.
之后我就赶紧撇下了她
I-I ditched her quick after that.
你也没告诉警方
And you didn't tell the police.
第一 有限制令
"A"… restraining order.
第二 我要说什么啊
"B"… what am I supposed to say?
我大半夜跟个12岁姑娘
I was hanging out talking murder.
一起闲聊凶杀案吗
with a 12-year-old girl in the middle of the night?
什么时候看到的标志
Where does the symbol come in?
在她肩膀上
She had it on her shoulder.
不知道是个疤 还是胎记
I don't know if it was a scar or… or a birthmark.
那姑娘什么样
What did this girl look like?
就姑娘样呗
A girl?
阿玛拉
Amara.
她说她叫这个
That's what she said her name was.
你认识她
You know her.
你说她12了
You said she was 12?
差不多吧
Well, maybe a little younger, or older.
她是谁啊
Who is she?
一个离家出走的孩子
She's a runaway.
你知道阿玛拉现在在哪吗
Do you know where Amara is now?
她还在镇上吗
Is she still in town?
我不知道 你找她做什么
I don't know. Why are you looking for her?
这我不能跟你说
I'm not at liberty to discuss that with you.
你必须告诉我 拜托了
You have to tell me. Please!
我必须找到她
I-I need to find her!
为什么
Why?
你不会信我的
You won't believe me.
好吧
Okay. Well,
好好看吧
enjoy your Lizzie fest.
别动手啊
No touching.
我可没碰你
I-I never touched you.
我不知道那女孩对我做了什么
I don't know what that girl did to me,
但那之后我一直不对劲
but I haven't been right since.
我吃不下 睡不着
I can't eat or sleep.
也不做梦
I-I don't dream.
我以前喜欢的一切
And all the things I used to love…
我的莉兹博客 鬼魂大会
my Lizzie blog, the ghost conventions…
都让我毫无感觉
they leave me cold.
我昨晚把整个收藏都摆上了易趣网
I-I put this whole collection on ebay last night.
现在都归俄亥俄州一个机械工了
Now it belongs to some machinist in Ohio.
你不是享乐的铁杆粉管理者吗
Well, what about the superfan curator living the bliss?
就是在扮演从前的我而已
Just playing the part of what I used to be.
装到成真嘛
You know, fake it till you make it.
或者到有感觉
Or feel it.
你今晚去旅馆就是为了这个吗
So, is that what you were doing at the inn tonight…
装
Faking it?
不是
No.
我是去找阿玛拉了
I was looking for Amara.
我想让她把我恢复过来
I want her to put me back.
我一直都…不合群
I've always been…odd.
古怪
and quirky.
但我至少还有份生活 有朋友
But I had a life, friends.
现在 我还记得怎么跟人说话
And now I remember how to talk to people,
该说什么
what to say,
但我感觉好像在演戏一样
but I feel like I'm acting,
只是在走过场
going through the motions.
我就像个机器人木偶
I'm like a robot puppet man.
阿玛拉来过 怎么会
Wait, Amara was here? How?
更疯狂的是 她现在12了
Oh, and the real crazy… apparently, she's like 12.
什么 这怎么可能
What? How is that even possible?
而且她吃的不是小麦干
It ain't wheaties she's eating. I'll tell you that much.
什么意思
Meaning?
伦 他状况不太好
Len… he ain't doing so hot.
我觉得阿玛拉吸食了她的灵魂
I think Amara sucked out his soul.
阿玛拉在像草一样疯长吗
So, Amara's growing like a radioactive weed?
是啊 因为她在大吃灵魂
Yeah, by stuffing her face with souls.
那么她的力量也更强了吗
Does that mean she's gaining more power, too?
为什么啊
And for what?
不知道 那个我们是躲不掉的
I don't know. That tsunami's gonna hit us sooner or later.
现在 我们只能对付我们能对付的
Right now we've got to deal with what we can deal with…
阿玛拉留下的这些空壳子
All these spent shells Amara's leaving behind.
你不会觉得伦是那个斧子狂人吧
You don't think Len's our Lizzie Borden, do you?
不 我问过他的邻居
No, I-I talked to his neighbors,
除了在旅馆被我碰见
and except for me seeing him at the b&b,
他整晚都在这里
he's been here all night.
我们不能杀他 他还没干过坏事呢
So, we can't kill him 'cause he hasn't done anything yet.
迪恩 我们也不想杀他啊
Dean, we don't…want to kill him.
我们是想救人的 记得吗
We want to save people, remember?
是啊 你的新规矩
Right, your new rules.
他怎么还没杀人啊
Why hasn't he offed anybody?
珍娜走下楼梯的光景
I mean, it took Jenna all of walking downstairs.
就决定去割她奶奶喉咙了
to slit her grandmother's throat.
不知道 或许不是每个被吸干灵魂的人
I don't know. Maybe not everybody Who gets their soul sucked out.
都会变成杀手
turns into a killer.
或许他是还没来得及
Or maybe he just hasn't gotten around to it yet.
好吧 我想我们最好
All right, well, I think the best thing is.
盯紧他 直到想到解决办法
we just stick close until we figure out how to help him out,
不过首先 你得告诉他 他没魂了
which starts by you telling him he's got no soul.
- 我吗 - 对
- Me? - Yeah.
凭什么是我去
Why do I have to do it?
因为你经历过
Well, because you've been there.
你能理解他
You speak the language.
他还不知道自己被吸了
He doesn't even know he's been hoovered yet.
但你跟他关系比我好啊
Yeah, but you have a better relationship with him than I do.
但你更会说话安慰人什么的
Yeah, but you're better with that whole sensitive verbal massage.
要怎么「安慰」地跟人说
There is no sensitive way to tell somebody.
他的灵魂被一个史前恶魔吸干了啊
their soul has been sucked out by a prehistoric tween!
就算伦真信我们
And even if Len does believe us,
那难道会让他感觉好点吗
is that supposed to make him feel better?
好吧
Fine.
他大概也承受不住真相
Probably couldn't handle the truth, anyway.
他现在有点脆弱
He's a little… little fragile right now.
好吧 那好 就这样
Okay, well, great.
那么我们要看护一个30岁大老爷们了
Looks like we're babysitting a 30-year-old man.
阿玛拉可能还吸了一个人
There may be someone else Amara got to, as well.
- 斧子杀人狂 - 对
- Our hatchet man. - Yeah.
凶案就是
So, the murders started.
在伦看到阿玛拉之后开始的 是吧
right around the time Len saw Amara, right?
上一位被害人的妻子 唐恩·平斯基
Well, the wife of the last victim… Dawn Pinski…
听到丈夫被杀时
had this bizarre reaction.
反应很奇怪
to hearing her husband got minced.
她根本毫不在乎
I mean, like she couldn't care less.
我没魂的时候就是那个感觉
That's kind of the way I felt the whole time I was soulless.
是啊 你当时就是个冷血机器人
Oh, yeah, you were one chilly droid.
总之 警探认为她是受了惊
Anyways, detective thinks it's shock,
但我想 或许妈妈没了魂 拿起了斧子
but I think maybe mom lost her soul and picked up an ax.
喂
Hello?
希德妮 我是柯林斯探员
Sydney. This is Agent Collins.
我们想找平斯基太太
We're trying to find Mrs. Pinski.
你知道她可能去哪了吗
Do you have any idea where she might be?
不知道 她
No. She, uh…
她没说什么啊
she didn't mention anything.
唐恩今天让我不用去了
Dawn didn't want me to come over today.
希德妮 你现在卷入了一起联邦案件的调查
Sydney, you are a part of a federal murder investigation.
最好别对我们有任何隐瞒
You do not want to hold anything back from us.
好吧 有个地方 她可能去了那儿
Okay, there might be one place that she could be.
唐恩有个朋友…叫奈特…
Dawn has a friend … Nate …
是个特别的朋友
a special friend.
好 我懂你的意思
Okay, I'm reading your mail.
听着 我不想害唐恩惹上麻烦
Look, I don't want to get Dawn in trouble.
你知道地址吗
Do you have an address?
喵星人视频 鸡肉和华夫饼
Kitten videos, chicken and waffles,
桉树香水 这些都不能激起我的兴趣了
eucalyptus scent … don't care for it anymore.
曾经很迷黑卷发
Used to swoon for dark, curly hair.
现在…也不了
Now … not so much.
你觉得我是中风了吗 还是长了脑瘤
Do you think I had a stroke? Or maybe it's a brain tumor.
真正诡异的
What's really freaky.
是所有以前会让我起鸡皮疙瘩的东西
is all the stuff that used to make my skin crawl.
如今看来…
now seems…
我之前都不能和人握手
I couldn't shake a guy's hand before.
天呐 那湿乎乎的感觉
God, that wetness.
现在我可以舔掉陌生人身上的汗…
Now I could lick the sweat off a stranger's …
- 行了 - 真的 舔身上任何一个地方
- Okay. - Yeah, any body part.
真的 我觉得好奇怪 兄弟
I'm serious. I-I feel weird, man.
怎么个奇怪法
"Weird" how?
像是…有东西正在我体内孵化
Like, something's hatching inside of me …
黑暗的东西
something dark,
还长了…翅膀
with…wings.
- 怎么了 - 没事
- What? - Nothing.
不 你看了萨姆一眼 像是…
But … no, you looked at Sam like …
你们知道我出什么问题了
you guys know what's wrong with me.
你没灵魂了 明白了吗
You don't have a soul, all right?
阿玛拉把你的灵魂吸走了
Amara sucked it out.
什么…
Wha…
迪恩
Dean.
你要不要更直接了当一点
You want to be a little more blunt?
那怎么可能
H-how is that even possible?
这只是为了避免你惹上麻烦 明白吗
Look, this is just so you don't get in trouble, all right?
我们马上回来
We'll be right back,
然后我们再考虑该拿你怎么办
and then we'll figure out what to do with you.
我要怎么拿回…我的灵魂
Well, how do … how do I get it back … my soul?
一般来说 是拿不回来了
Generally, you don't.
终于知道了感觉还不错
It feels good to finally know.
有人吗
Hello?
里面出事了
Something happened in here.
蓝车是妈妈的 我昨晚看见了
Well, the blue car's the mom's. I saw it last night.
乔迪
Jordie?
伙计
Hey, buddy.
你没事吧
You all right?
马上就好
Give me a sec.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
真不敢相信自己把你俩都抓住了
I can't believe that I bagged both of you guys.
是啊 所以是希德妮
Yeah, so it's, uh, Sydney,
杀手保姆 不是妈妈
the killer babysitter, not the mom.
你打算怎么办
So, what's the story?
准备像砍死其他人那样砍死我们吗
Are you gonna hack us up like the others?
我不玩那套了
I'm … I'm past that.
你俩是我给我新朋友的祭品
You two are an offering to my new friend.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你的新闺蜜是阿玛拉吗
Is your new bestie Amara?
你知道她
You know her?
可不是嘛 我们关系可铁了
Oh, yeah, we're tight.
你俩怎么碰上的
How did you two meet?
几晚前 我喝得烂醉
A couple nights ago, I got pretty sloshed.
（莫莉的小斧屋）
有个自以为是的 做信托基金的人渣
This, uh, smug, little trust-fund dirtbag.
把我甩了
just dumped me.
打扰一下 醉妞
Excuse me? Drunk girl?
你不应该开车的
You shouldn't be driving.
你可能会把头伸出窗外
You could put your head through a window.
你父母呢
Uh, where are your parents?
他们居然在工作日晚上带你来这种破地方
They bring you to this dump on a school night?
我爸妈也这么干过
My parents used to do that.
我是自己找到这地方的
I found this place on my own.
我喜欢黑暗的地方
I like dark places.
你是一个人来的吗
You're here alone?
好吧 我…
Okay, let's, uh…
我送你上车吧
let's get you inside.
对了 我叫希德妮
I'm Sydney, by the way.
我会帮助你的 希德妮
I'm going to help you, Sydney.
你觉得我需要帮助吗
You think I need help?
也许你说得对
Well, um, maybe you're right.
至少今晚需要
Tonight, anyway.
你是怎么…
How did …
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
我感觉…
Oh, I feel like…
我感觉像是摇头丸高潮巧克力蛋糕
I feel like ecstasy-orgasm chocolate cake.
你是个天使
You're an angel.
我看着像个长翅膀的唠叨鬼马屁精吗
Do I look like a whiny, winged suck-up?
那么 你是什么
Well, then, what are you?
你们看过一个冰茶广告吗
Have you guys ever seen the iced-tea commercial.
里面有个女的躺在橡皮筏上
where the lady is lying on the inflatable raft,
在闪闪发光的池子里漂着
and she's just drifting along a sparkling pool?
那就是和阿玛拉在一起的感觉
That's what it was like being with Amara …
极乐
Bliss.
没有伤痛 没有悲伤
No hurting, no sadness,
也没有记忆
no memories.
你不想要记忆吗
So you don't want memories?
你有对好父母吗 萨姆
Did you have nice parents, Sam?
因为在我爸妈眼中 我和我妹妹
Because my folks treated me and my sister.
就是人肉烟灰缸
like human ashtrays.
我曾经喝酒麻痹自己 就因为不敢看伤口
I used to have to drink myself blind to even look at these,
更别说给别人看了
let alone show anybody.
而如今 我不知道阿玛拉对我做了什么
And now I don't know what Amara did to me,
但这只是皮而已
but it's just skin.
好吧…那真是…恭喜你了
Right, well, that's really…good for you.
再也不会从噩梦中惊醒
No more waking up screaming from nightmares.
再不会回忆起过去
No more flashbacks.
阿玛拉带走了痛苦
Amara took away the pain.
她点亮了我的内心
She lightened something in me.
但你现在变成了斧子杀人犯
Except now you're an ax murderer.
我自由了
I'm free.
以前我脑海中总会回荡着一个声音
Before, there was always this constant voice in my head,
「你不可以那样做 那样不好
"You can't do that. It's wrong.
万一你被抓住了怎么办「
What if you get caught?"
现在终于安静了
And now it is quiet.
现在只剩下我和我心中的渴望
It is just me and what I want.
而当你可以随心所欲做任何事时
And when you can do whatever you want,
你根本不会被抓到
you don't have to get caught.
那时 你就可以真正飞翔了
And then you can really fly.
你把旅馆那对情侣砍成肉酱时 也飞翔了吗
Were you flying when you diced up that couple at the inn?
当我得知那个混蛋
When I found out that that pus hole.
又带了个女孩去开房时
was taking another girl to the B&B …
他就死定了
that's his deal-closing move …
我可不要窝在家里伤心流泪
I didn't have to sit at home and cry about it.
旅馆老板的妈妈又怎么惹你了
And what about the innkeeper's mom?
那个老东西
That piece of jerky …
她欠了我两周的薪水
she screwed me out of two weeks pay.
我曾经幻想如何杀死她
I used to fantasize about killing her,
现在我梦想已成真
and now I am living the dream.
难怪你可以进出无阻
So that's how you got in and out …
你曾在那里工作过
You worked there.
就干了一夏天
Just for one summer.
乔迪的父母呢
What about Jordie's parents, huh?
他们也欺负你了吗
What, did they screw you over, too?
不是我 是乔迪
Not me. Jordie.
该怎么说呢
Where to start?
爸爸贩毒 妈妈犯贱
Meth-dealing dad, slut mom.
我是救了乔迪
No, I saved Jordie.
我比他俩更能照顾好他
And I'm gonna take better care of him than they ever did.
你说我们俩是祭品
Well, you said that we were, uh … we were an offering.
你要怎么把阿玛拉找来
Well, how are you planning on bringing Amara here?
别跟我说那姑娘有手机
Don't tell me that girl's got a cellphone.
我一直在祈祷
I've been praying,
我知道她能听见我
and I know that she can hear me.
我能感觉得到
I can feel it.
她离我很近
She's close.
她还没离开我
She hasn't left me.
那就让她出来
Well, bring her on out.
我们追捕那贱人好几周了
We've been hunting that bitch for weeks.
她是女神
She is a Goddess!
天哪 我杀人了
Holy crap. I just did that.
我拿着吧
Take this away.
黑暗就要来了
The Darkness is coming.
它是那么平静
It's so peaceful.
它来找我们了
It's coming for all of us.
乔迪 你有什么亲戚家可以去借住吗
Jordie, you have any, uh, family you can stay with?
我六个月大时 我妈妈就死了
When I was 6 months old, my mom died,
我爸爸…
and my dad was…
几乎不怎么陪在我身边
was never really around much.
我知道这与你相比不算什么
I realize that's nowhere close to what you've lost,
但…你是能渡过难关的
but…You're gonna survive this.
大家都会来帮你的
People are gonna help you.
我有个凯茜姨妈
There's aunt Kathy.
她圣诞节时会过来
She comes at Christmas.
首先 我是把手直接从手铐里挣出来的
First of all, I ripped my hand out of the cuff.
你救了我们 伦
Well, you saved us, Len.
这不是我自残的理由
Yeah, that's not why I mauled myself.
我是想看看我能不能做到
I-I wanted to see if I could do it.
真是疼死个人
It hurt like a mother,
但我并没有崩溃
but it didn't wig me out at all.
我把自己的拇指捡起来 就跟捡迷你热狗肠一样
I picked up my thumb like it was a mini hot dog.
伦 说实话 这有点让人担心
Len, I'm not gonna lie. That's worrisome.
那个女孩
And that girl …
我的大脑说 我应该去帮你们
My brain said I should help you,
但我真的一点感觉都没有
but I-I didn't really feel anything…
无论是对你或她
For you or her.
什么样的人会杀死人还毫无感觉呢
What kind of person can murder and feel nothing?
伦 无论你内心有多少黑暗
Len, whatever Darkness you have inside you,
只要你还有一丝良知
if there's a shred of conscience,
那就还有希望
then there might be hope.
不 萨姆说灵魂一旦失去
No, Sam said once your soul is gone,
就再也回不来了
you can't get it back, and …
我很确定 如果没人阻拦我
and I-I know for sure now if I'm not stopped,
我会继续杀人的
there'll be another kill.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
就像泡泡在上升
Like a bubble rising up.
你想怎么办
So, what do you want to do?
你可以杀了我
You could kill me.
我不能
No, I can't … I…
我不想那么做
No, I don't want to do that.
那只有一个办法了
Then there's only one thing.
我去自首
I'm gonna turn myself in.
我会担下所有的凶案
I'll confess to all the murders.
那样我就出不来了
That way, I can't get out.
没有很多
Well, there's not too many…
没灵魂的杀手会去自首
soulless killers that would give themselves up.
我记得做正确的事是什么感觉
I remember what it was like to do the right thing.
所以趁我还能做到
So I'm … I'm going through the motions.
就继续走过场吧
for as long as I can.
不敢相信伦居然自首了
So, I can't believe Len turned himself in.
其实这样也说得通
I mean, it kind of makes sense, you know,
失去灵魂的人会有不同的反应
people having different reactions to losing their souls.
我就是
I did.
每个人都有自己的经历 对吧
Everyone's got their own history, right?
伦失去了心
Len loses his heart.
希德妮失去了头脑
Sydney loses her head.
接下来是什么 胆小的狮子吗
What are we looking for, the cowardly lion next?
你知道吗 每次我一想到她
You know, I get this, like, pit in my stomach.
我的胃就会痛
any time I think of her …
黑暗
The Darkness …
她是什么 她对人做什么
Like, we only know the tip of what she is,
我们只看到冰山一角
what she does to people.
伦被她吓得惊慌失措
You know, Len was freaked out by her,
但希德妮
But Sydney …
希德妮却欲罢不能
Sydney couldn't get enough.
她说是极乐
The…bliss she was talking about, you know?
对你来说是什么样的
What was it like for you?
你和阿玛拉在一起时有那种感觉吗
Did you feel like that with Amara?
没有
No.
没有 那时很平静
No, I mean, it was quiet,
直到
you know, till, uh.
直到她开始培养杀手
till she started hatching killers.
召集怪物组建军队
and rallying monsters to raise armies.
我们就只能这么找她了啊
So that's how we have to find her, huh?
跟着尸体
Follow the bodies?
你有更好的主意吗
You got a better idea?
我们可以追踪你看到的疯狂幻觉
We could follow the crazy you've been seeing.
按照阿玛拉的成长速度
Look, at the rate Amara's growing,
到处吸取灵魂 越来越强大
sucking souls and getting stronger,
她可能不会很难找到
she might not be that hard to find.
走吧
Come on.
再见 迪恩
Bye, Dean.
回头见了
I'll see you soon.